

www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran	in
alporan.github.io/blog	<u>_</u>
alporan@windowslive.com	
90 537 513 45 29	Ö

-

## **PROFILE**

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing and maintaining software systems. Quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Strong problem solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-manage during personal projects.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sekerbank T.A.Ş

Senior Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Main responsibilities;

- Developing applications for Internet and Mobile Branches by using Java, Spring Framework and Agile practices.
- Maintaining legacy JSP-Servlet based Java EE web-application.

# **BilgeAdam Technologies**

Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Working as a Consultant Software Developer at Şekerbank T.A.Ş

### **Turkish Airlines**

Software Engineer, 2017-2020

Main responsibilities;

- Developing mainframe applications for reservation, ticketing and DCS systems using Java Technologies,
  IBM High Level Assembler and Agile practices.
- Migrating mainframe applications to the open systems as part of architectural transformation projects.
- Maintenance of code base and database records.
- Solving dumps and system errors.
- Automating manual tasks and test cases with Python Programming Language.
- Providing support for teams utilizing mainframe programs.

## **EDUCATION**

## **MASTER OF SCIENCE**, Information Technologies

Sakarya University, 2018-2019

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Istanbul Technical University, 2011-2015

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Personal Webpage**

Static webpage for presenting my portfolio and blogging.

**Tools:** Jekyll, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Link:** https://alporan.github.io/blog

## **Clinic Appointment Application**

Implementing CRUD operations for simple clinic appointment application.

Tools: MySQL, Angular, Spring Boot frameworks.

**Link:** <a href="https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app">https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app</a>

#### Attachmate Extra! X-treme Macro Interface

Interface for developing utility programs and macros with Python programming language for Extra! X-treme terminals.

Tools: Python, PyQt5, Extra! X-treme API

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface

#### **Blazing Fruits**

Android game checks multitasking and hand-eye coordination.

Tools: Java, Android Studio, libGDX Library

Link: <a href="https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing">https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing</a> fruits

## An Indoor Localization Algorithm On FPGA

Multiple RF reader modules were localized by using received signal strength value from stationary RFID tags. Localization algorithm was implemented on an FPGA.

Tools: Verilog, C++, FPGAs

Link: https://web.itu.edu.tr/~orssi/thesis/2015/AlpOran bit.pdf

# **SKILLS**

# **Programming Languages & Frameworks**

- Java
- Spring Framework
- Spring Boot
- Jakarta EE
- IBM High-Level Assembler Language
- SQL
- Python
- Hibernate
- JUnit

### **Tools**

- Git
- GitHub / BitBucket
- Relational Databases
- JIRA
- CA Endevor SCM
- CA Clarity PPM

# **LANGUAGES & TEST SCORES**

**Turkish**: Native or bilingual proficiency **English**: Full professional proficiency

IELTS (International English Language Testing System), Nov 2015

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

Overall Score: 7.5/9

TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), Jul 2015

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

Total Score: 92/120